Hey, welcome back. In this video, we're
going to be talking about one very
special feature of Studio 2.0, which is
the ability to create your own unique
plugins. So, I pulled up this project
that just has a few tracks on it. If
you've watched some of our other videos,
you might recognize the song. And it
sounds like this.
And that sounds pretty nice, but I'd
love to find some ways to make this
keyboard part sound a little bit more
interesting. In this Studio 2.0
interface, I can double-click on a track
to open up this bottom effects panel.
And I can add effects like
uh compressor or a delay.
But, what if I want to do something that
isn't one of the built-in seven plugins
that we have already? Well, with the
Studio chat, which you access by
hovering here or by clicking enter, you
can ask to create a new plugin. So,
there's a bunch of different things we
can consider here. Maybe we create a
plugin that, you know, add some like
warm like tape style saturation. Maybe
we want to do something experimental
that involves pitch shifting things.
Maybe I want like a stereo doubler. Or
maybe we try to make them all into like
one thing, who knows? Make new plugin
that is a stereo
doubler
and adds saturation. And I'm going to
let it kind of actually figure out how
it's going to design the doubler part
from a signal chain perspective. It
should have a knob.
It should have knobs for width,
warmth, mix,
and
crunch, which I'll let it kind of figure
out what these are going to mean. And if
I press one,
I can open up the chat and see the
long-form conversation that I'm having
with this little Studio chat agent. And
now it's gotten back to me with a plan.
Let's take a look.
So, width, yep, the spread of doubled
voices, warmth is going to be a tilt
towards even harmonics, nice, and crunch
is the amount of odd harmonics. That
sounds good. Mix is going to be the dry
wet blend, which feels appropriate.
Build it. So, while this is working, I
should note that the plugin that gets
created right now is unique to your
account. So, it'll only exist for other
people if you send them this plugin
embedded in one of the projects that you
share. And then, once you've created it
one time, it'll always live in a special
part of your plugin library called my
plugins. So, you can see if I say add
effect, there's this my plugins section
at the top here. And this is where the
plugins that I've made in the past live.
In my case, I've created chaos engine
and chaos storm. And now you can see
that stereo doubler plus saturator has
just loaded on in. So, let's bring this
to the track and see what it sounds
like. I should probably put on some
headphones to see if this is working.
Woof. Okay, it seems like it wired up
our width backwards, where 0% is all the
way wide and 100% is mono. This is
technology that's still in development,
so
uh we'll work on ironing out some of
those kinks. But, in any case, the
plugin is sounding really nice.
Woof.
Okay, let's make another one. Um how
about please create a plugin
that
pitches
the audio
up
um an octave
and delays it around
really fast to make the audio sound
sparkly. You can figure out the UI. And
we're going to see what we get back.
Okay, crystal sparkle. It's ready to go.
Let's take a listen.
Oof.
Now, that's kind of funky. So, now we
have the stereo doubler plus saturator
and Crystal Sparkle in our plugin
library. And the ability to imagine a
brand new plugin that's unique to you
sort of is the ability to imagine like a
new way to manipulate audio itself.
Anytime you go to U Studio, you'll have
these available as plugins that you can
use and lean on. Just another way to
build a unique style.
I actually want to just try adding these
to my drum track and see how they sound.
Specifically, the doubler and saturator.
Let's update the width. I've been having
trouble with this width slider. I just
learned that if you option-click, you
can edit that value by hand.
Cool. So, that's knocking. This was
plugin authoring 101 with Insuna Studio.
Going forward, we have a lot of ideas
for plugins we want to bring in here,
but we also want to enable you all to
share your plugins with each other. Um
maybe there's cool ways to trade plugins
and maybe even transact around on
someday. So, let us know what you think
in the comments. Let us know how we can
make this better. I know for me
personally, I want to see some sort of
vocal tuning plugin. So, hopefully we
can get that in here soon. Thank you so
much for watching. Please drop any
plugin ideas you have down in the
comments below and I'll see you in the
next one.
>> Woo!